[yellow]Summer Festival Notice; [white] Cherry Tree Park}
same as above}
…Summertime Memories.}
same}
Sena Girls’ Academy}
[left] Clean-up; [right]Pool}
Mizuhashi}
Summer Festival Grounds Headquarters; [on tent] Yomogi Shops}
Mikan}
Strap Corner}
[bottom left] Yomogi Station; [top right] Summer Sale}
Yamada Cameras}
same as above}
ibid}
Mizuhashi}
[blue field, white letters] NOTICE; [white field, black letters] New E-mail: 1/Na-chan; [bottom, white box]Options}
[blue field, white letters] Main Folder; [beside envelope] Na-chan; [cream field, black letters] Subject: I’m Sorry!; [blue letters]Attached Files: 1; [boxes left to right]Settings; Options; Menu}
Same}
Displaying}
[bottom boxes left to right] E-mail; Save; Menu]
The Organ And The Boy Upon That Day}
Now listen up, Kobato…
The summer vacation is our rival, okay?
Rival, you say?
That’s right! With a summer vacation you have…
Beaches!
Bug collecting!
Watermelon splitting!
There are just too many ways it can distract you from helping those who are hurting…
Hey, you listening, Dobato?!
A letter!
It’s not a letter! It’s a flier! A flier!
I don’t need to tell you that collecting confetti will be a constant struggle.
Especially with summer festivals being such formidable enemies.
Flutes, drums and yukatas at temple festivals.
And then there are the Bon dances.
They look beautiful!
Huh?
Now listen up, Kobato!
You'd better understand what I’m trying to say!
We’re not done talking here!
I won’t give in to the summer festivals!
I will heal everyone whose hearts are hurting!
A summer festival.
Where did it go, I wonder?
Do you mean this?
Yes! That’s it!
Thank you very much.
Just a second.
Here, use this.
Huh?
Your hands are all wet.
Thank you very much!
What is she up to now?
It’s a flier for a summer festival!
It is the season for them, after all.
Have you ever gone to one?
Every year since I was a kid.
Ported shrines and fireworks at the temple.
“Fire-flowers…”
But…
I might not go this year.
Why is that?
Hey, let’s have a race at the pool!
Sure, and I’m not going to lose!
Yeah? But, you know, I’ve
gotten better at swimming!
Really?
I have to get going.
High schools are still in session today.
Yomogi Preschool is on summer break!
Huh?
Ow…
Yukino?
Na-chan! Good morning!
You were too busy looking at
your cell-phone, weren’t you?
If you keep messing around, you’ll be late.
Are you all right?
Ko-ba-tooo!
Ioryogi-san!
My body feels h-heavy.
Is that better?
It’s not better!
No sooner had I warned you, than you fell for the summer festival!
Stay right there!
I’m going to make you feel the heat!
Dry me out.
That uniform is from Sena Girls’ Academy.
So you know Nachan-san, Fujimoto-san?
No.
It’s the high school annexed to the women’s college.
It’s Sayaka-san’s and Chitose-san’s alma mater.
You know so much!
It’s a school for upper-crust girls. Not for girls like you.
He is being mean today.
Since he’s on break from the preschool,
he’s probably overly busy with work and studying.
Oh…
In any case, I’m dry now.
You’re giving that back, right?
That’s right!
Nachan-san isn’t anywhere!
Hurry it up before it gets dark!
I would like to make an announcement before you all leave for summer break.
There she is!
Mizuhashi Natsuki-san has been recognized,
for her beautification work with the
volunteer club where she represents us.
We’ve received a thank-you letter
from the prefecture for her efforts.
So Nachan-san's name is Mizuhashi Natsuki-san.
And that stumbling girl is in the same class.
Take care not to stay up too late during summer break.
From this morning…
And take care not to slack off either.
The students from Sena Academy are
expected to maintain a certain standard…
Morikawa-san! You again?!
Shape up or it will be confiscated!
So-
Sorry.
Now then, we will be confirming your
emergency contacts for summer break.
Oh, nice picture!
If anything were to happen…
You really have an eye for it!
You really think so?
Come on, have a little pride!
That is all.
Please gather by the side of the pool for clean-up duty.
They’re coming!
Yes!
Excuse me-
Are you a student here?
No. I’m Hanato Kobato from Yomogi Preschool.
Preschool? What are you talking about?
You there, please call for the clerk.
Damn it all. Kobato, run for it!
Why is that?
Come on, just go!
Okay, I’ll try.
Ah, hey!
Hold it right there!
In any case, we have to find Natsuki-san.
Are you holding the lens correctly?
Real ones are great!
Isn’t it about time you bought yourself one, Yukino-chi?
Oh…
That girl was with Na-chan this morning.
So your name is Yukino-san?
Yeah.
My name is Hanato Kobato.
Na-chan!
This girl needs to see you for something.
Oh, we met this morning.
I, Hanato Kobato, have come to return your hankerchief!
You even washed it for me?
Yes. But since I don’t have an iron,
it’s all wrinkled. I’m sorry.
That’s okay.
Thanks a lot!
W-Well, I’ll be going.
Huh? What about the pool cleaning?
Sorry, I haven’t told you this,
but I have a part-time job now.
But this school doesn’t
allow us to work part-time.
I know that...
Yukino-chi!
Yukino!
Sorry we’re late!
It’s okay!
Na-chan, I’m really sorry!
Yukino!
Yukino-chi is working to buy a new camera.
We’ll be taking her place for the
pool-cleaning, so please don’t tell.
I had no idea.
Excuse me, Natsuki-san!
I-I will join you!
It is just as Fujimoto-san said!
This place is not like ours at all!
Still, nobody uses “I will
join you!” as a pick-up line.
“Pick-up line?” People don’t do that?
Sorry to make you wait.
Um. I’m sorry for using a pick-up line!
I actually didn’t want to go home alone,
so I was happy you did.
Then that’s great.
That photograph…
That looks like Yukino-san.
It was taken during a summer
festival while we were in grade school.
You two are very close!
I guess you can say we were close.
So you two aren’t close right now?
Well…
…Yukino has grown distant from me.
Na-chan, good morning!
Good morning, Yukino-chan!
Your shirt is sticking out in the back.
I’ll fix it for you.
We used to go to school together every morning.
Sorry for being so late!
Yukino-chan, you’ve got really bad bedhair!
You’re kidding! Hold on for a minute!
Yukino-chan, hurry back!
And then, at some point…
Sorry, Na-chan, I overslept! Go on without me!
Yeah, sure.
And then, when we got to
high school, we just slowly…
And then… huh?
That’s beautiful!
Sorry, Na-chan. Go ahead without me.
Um, sure.
Yukino-chan, if you’re so interested in photography, then join our club!
But for me to join a club…
Now don’t be like that.
Why not just have a look-see?
Yeah, well…
It’ll be fine, don’t worry!
Now recently, we’ve grown completely apart.
I don’t know what Yukino
is thinking about anymore…
I want to help Natsuki-san!
How?
I don’t know!
What do you mean you don’t know?!
Anyway, I have to go meet with Yukino-san.
Good job there!
We should be able to make it for the festival now.
Yes.
Take whatever you like.
I’m very sorry for disturbing you at work.
It’s all right. I’m done anyway, so don’t worry.
Is that so?
I’ve saved up enough money.
And I’ll be going to the sale at the station
building tomorrow to finally buy my camera.
So the one you had yesterday wasn’t yours?
Yesterday?
Oh!
That was a friend’s.
I want my own so much that I’ve been working for a while now.
That’s amazing, Yukino-san!
I originally got interested when I was taking pictures with my cell-phone.
Now I’m completely hooked.
I made friends with some
girls in the Photography Club.
There’s so much we can talk about.
What about Natsuki-san?
You haven’t been talking to Natsuki-san?
Na-chan was… an old friend of mine.
They match!
Yup!
Hey, let’s go buy straps.
I think they should match too!
But if the straps match too, we can’t tell them apart.
You’re right.
I’ll take this.
Then, I’ll take this.
I’ll take a watermelon, since I’m Natsuki.
And since I’m Yukino, I’ll have a snowman.
Too cute!
Why don’t we trade?
Sure!
I will treasure it!
I’ll treasure it too!
So you’re no longer close with Natsuki-san?
Have you come to hate her?
I would never… I could never hate Na-chan!
I wish I could be Na-chan.
Stop that, you’re embarrassing me!
Say, let’s take one together.
Sure!
All right, cheese!
Next time we should take a real one!
Then you should get better at taking pictures.
I think Natsuki-san and Yukino-san...
...really want to be close to each other.
Why can’t they be close like they used to?
Who knows.
If they don’t even know,
how could we possibly know?
But... I want to do something.
Excuse me! Where is the
camera seller for this sale located?
If you’re looking for that…
Yes!
Hey, since you bought it, why don’t you try it out?
That sounds great!
Oh… Na-chan.
Out shopping?
Uh… yeah.
It’s a single-lens reflex camera.
Really?
Y-Yukino-chi has been working hard
at her job to buy this great camera.
That’s right!
Even us in the photography club are jealous.
Yukino-chi, you should really join our club!
That would be awesome!
Do it to commemorate your single-lens debut!
Especially since you bought the camera of your dreams!
That’s right!
Next time, let’s go to a photography exhibition!
You’re sure to take some
good pictures with your talent!
Come on!
Please?
This is idiotic!
I could see that you were good enough... if you were taking pictures for ads.
But too many people have it wrong.
Yukino, can’t you see the mistake you’re making?
You’re just some no-talent amateur who thinks she’s a pro. You’re despicable!
Yukino-san!
Natsuki-san!
Yukino-san…
I think it would be great if I had the talent.
But all I have now…
...is my joy of taking pictures…
...and my love for cameras.
Um… uh… It’s great that you bought the camera you love.
From there-
Sorry.
I want to be alone right now.
Okay.
Why did I blurt out those things?
It’s gone.
The strap is gone!
How?
Not here.
Hey. Where are you going now?
Natsuki-san was not being very nice back there.
So I need to say something to her.
Like what?
Well… anyway, things cannot continue on like this!
May I ask what happened?
It’s gone! The strap is gone!
I will help you out!
I already searched through
those, and I still can’t find it!
What am I going to do?
I was so cruel to Yukino.
So that’s why it’s gone missing!
In any case, I’ll look for it!
What now?
I… I…
Natsuki-san.
Natsuki-san…
There it is!
Thank you!
Thank you, Kobato-chan!
You and Yukino-san really are still close, aren’t you?
Yukino is probably afraid of me.
Perhaps that made all her efforts so wonderful.
Yukino…
has always been peculiar.
Then, slowly, I felt us drifting further apart.
I was really afraid that she’d leave me for good.
That’s why I focused my efforts on my studying and other stuff.
But I was the one who grew apart…
…from her.
Natsuki-san. Could you
possibly lend me your telephone?
Na-chan…
You still have it…
Yukino-san.
Yukino… I was really mean to you earlier…
Um…
We’re the same.
Look… I’ve also been keeping it.
Yukino…
I’ve also always been keeping it.
Have you ever fought with
Chitose-san, Sayaka-sensei?
Have we fought? Only so
many times that I’ve lost count!
Oh, did we really?
How many times have we
refused to speak to each other?
That’s right. It did happen sometimes.
But you two are still close.
Na-chan, smile!
What? You’re embarrassing me!
The fireworks are beautiful!
Today you get 90 points, so take it, you thief!
Huh?
The fireworks are beautiful!
What the hell are you doing getting cheered up by the summer festival!
That’s it! I’m giving you minus 200 points, Dobato!
The fireworks are beautiful!
What the hell! Listen to me, dammit!
So beautiful!